<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AnimalPedia</string>

    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="about_name">Rahma Bintang Pratama</string>
    <string name="about_description">Email: rahmabintangp@gmail.com</string>

    <string name="this_is_detailactivity">Ini MoveActivity</string>

    <string name="animal_name">Animal Name</string>
    <string name="description">Description</string>
    <string name="app_motto">Make introducing your child to animals more enjoyable</string>
    <string-array name="data_name">
        <item>Crocodile</item>
        <item>Deer</item>
        <item>Dolphin</item>
        <item>Elephant</item>
        <item>Gorilla</item>
        <item>Horse</item>
        <item>Lion</item>
        <item>Orca</item>
        <item>Parrot</item>
        <item>Snake</item>
        <item>Tiger</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="data_description">
        <item>Crocodiles are carnivorous reptiles known as powerful predators in aquatic environments, especially in tropical and subtropical regions worldwide. With large and heavy bodies, crocodiles have strong jaws equipped with sharp teeth, and their skin is covered with tough scales as protection. Their body length varies depending on the species, ranging from a few feet to over 20 feet, with skin colors ranging from dark brown to grayish-green, aiding in camouflage. Crocodiles are typically found in freshwater habitats such as rivers, swamps, and lakes, although some species can also be found in brackish water or even coastal areas. They have strong adaptations for life in water, with tails allowing them to swim quickly and with high speed. As efficient predators, crocodiles prey on a variety of prey, including fish, amphibians, reptiles, birds, small mammals, and even large animals such as deer or buffalo. They employ patient waiting tactics before swiftly attacking their prey. In terms of reproduction, crocodiles are nesting animals, with females typically laying eggs in protected areas near water, and they are highly protective of their nests and offspring after they hatch. Additionally, crocodiles play a significant role in the aquatic ecosystems they inhabit by helping to control the populations of other animals and maintaining ecosystem balance. Although sometimes perceived as a threat to humans, it is important to understand that crocodiles have a significant role in ecology and need to be preserved in conservation efforts.</item>
        <item>Deer, known scientifically as members of the Cervidae family, are graceful herbivorous mammals found in various ecosystems across the globe. They are characterized by their slender bodies, long legs, and branching antlers (in males of most species), which are shed and regrown annually. Deer exhibit a wide range of sizes, from the small, delicate muntjac to the majestic red deer and elk. Their coats vary in coloration depending on the species and habitat, ranging from reddish-brown to grayish hues, often featuring spots or patterns that aid in camouflage. Deer are predominantly found in forested areas, grasslands, and shrublands, where they feed on a diet consisting mainly of vegetation, including grasses, leaves, shoots, and twigs. They are known for their agility and speed, allowing them to evade predators with quick leaps and bounds. During the mating season, known as the rut, males compete for dominance and mating rights by engaging in elaborate displays, vocalizations, and occasionally, physical combat. Females give birth to one or two fawns after a gestation period, and they provide maternal care and protection to their offspring. Deer play a vital role in their ecosystems as both herbivores and prey species, contributing to the balance of plant communities and serving as a food source for carnivores. While admired for their beauty and grace, deer populations face various threats, including habitat loss, hunting, and predation, highlighting the importance of conservation efforts to ensure their survival and the integrity of their habitats.</item>
        <item>Dolphins, known scientifically as cetaceans of the family Delphinidae, are highly intelligent and social marine mammals inhabiting oceans and seas worldwide. They are characterized by their streamlined bodies, curved dorsal fins, and sleek, hydrodynamic shape, which enable them to navigate through water with remarkable agility and speed. Dolphins display a range of sizes and colors depending on the species; some are relatively small, such as the Maui\'s dolphin, while others, like the orca or killer whale, can grow quite large. Their skin coloration typically varies from shades of gray to blue, sometimes accompanied by distinctive patterns or markings unique to each individual. Dolphins are renowned for their playful behavior, often seen riding waves, leaping out of the water, and interacting with each other in complex social structures. They communicate through a sophisticated system of clicks, whistles, and body language, facilitating coordination during hunting, navigation, and social bonding. Diet-wise, dolphins are carnivores, feeding on fish, squid, and other small marine creatures, employing cooperative hunting strategies to catch their prey. They are also known to exhibit altruistic behavior, aiding injured or distressed individuals within their pod. Reproduction in dolphins typically involves females giving birth to a single calf after a gestation period, and both parents participate in the care and protection of the offspring. Dolphins play a crucial role in marine ecosystems as top predators, helping to regulate the populations of prey species and maintaining the balance of the food chain. Despite their intelligence and adaptability, dolphins face numerous threats, including habitat degradation, pollution, bycatch in fishing gear, and disturbance from human activities. Conservation efforts are essential to safeguarding dolphin populations and ensuring the health and integrity of their marine habitats for future generations.</item>
        <item>Elephants, majestic creatures belonging to the family Elephantidae, are among the largest land animals on Earth, characterized by their massive size, distinctively long trunks, and large, flapping ears. They come in two main species: the African elephant and the Asian elephant, each with its own unique characteristics and habitats. African elephants, the larger of the two species, roam the grasslands, savannas, and forests of sub-Saharan Africa, while Asian elephants inhabit the forests and grasslands of South and Southeast Asia. Elephants possess remarkable intelligence and exhibit complex social structures within their herds, which are typically led by the oldest and most experienced female, known as the matriarch. These highly social animals engage in intricate forms of communication, using a combination of vocalizations, body language, and infrasound to convey messages and coordinate group activities. Their trunks, elongated muscular structures comprised of thousands of muscles, serve a multitude of purposes, including breathing, smelling, drinking, and grasping objects, enabling them to manipulate food, interact with their environment, and show affection towards one another. In addition to their trunks, elephants are characterized by their impressive tusks, which are elongated incisor teeth, unfortunately making them targets for poaching. Elephants are herbivores, primarily feeding on grasses, leaves, bark, fruits, and roots, and they play a crucial role in shaping their ecosystems by dispersing seeds, creating pathways through dense vegetation, and modifying their habitats in various ways. Despite facing threats such as habitat loss, human-wildlife conflict, and illegal poaching, conservation efforts aimed at protecting elephant populations and their habitats are essential for ensuring the survival of these magnificent creatures for future generations to admire and appreciate.</item>
        <item>Gorillas, the largest of the living primates, are remarkable creatures found in the dense forests of central Africa. These gentle giants belong to the Hominidae family and share a striking resemblance to humans, with robust bodies, broad chests, and imposing yet gentle demeanors. Gorillas are primarily ground-dwelling and predominantly herbivorous, feeding on a diet consisting of leaves, shoots, fruits, and occasionally insects. They live in cohesive family groups led by a dominant silverback male, who is responsible for protecting the group and maintaining order within the troop. Gorillas exhibit complex social structures, forming strong bonds through grooming, vocalizations, and physical gestures. Their expressive faces and rich vocal repertoire allow for intricate communication within the group, facilitating cooperation and social cohesion. Despite their formidable appearance, gorillas are generally peaceful animals, preferring to resolve conflicts through displays of dominance rather than aggression. However, they face numerous threats to their survival, including habitat loss, poaching, and disease. Conservation efforts aimed at protecting gorilla habitats and promoting sustainable ecotourism play a vital role in ensuring the long-term survival of these magnificent primates. Gorillas serve as flagship species for the preservation of the rich biodiversity of their forest habitats, embodying the interconnectedness of all life forms in the delicate balance of the natural world.</item>
        <item>Horses, iconic and majestic animals belonging to the Equidae family, have long been revered for their beauty, strength, and versatility. Domesticated by humans for thousands of years, horses have played crucial roles in transportation, agriculture, warfare, and leisure activities. Characterized by their slender bodies, powerful legs, flowing mane, and expressive eyes, horses come in a variety of breeds, each with its own unique characteristics and abilities. They are renowned for their speed, agility, and endurance, making them ideal companions for various equestrian disciplines such as racing, show jumping, dressage, and rodeo events. Horses exhibit complex social behaviors, forming strong bonds within herds and displaying hierarchical structures led by dominant individuals. Their communication involves a rich array of vocalizations, body language, and facial expressions, allowing for intricate interactions and social cohesion. Horses are herbivores, primarily feeding on grasses, hay, grains, and other plant matter, with specialized digestive systems designed for efficient utilization of fibrous vegetation. Despite their domestication, horses retain many of their innate instincts and behaviors, including flight responses to perceived threats and the formation of strong social bonds. Today, horses continue to captivate the human imagination, symbolizing freedom, grace, and companionship. However, they also face challenges such as habitat loss, overbreeding, and neglect, highlighting the importance of responsible stewardship and compassionate care for these magnificent animals. Through education, advocacy, and conservation efforts, we can ensure the welfare and well-being of horses for generations to come, honoring their enduring legacy as beloved companions and partners in human history.</item>
        <item>Lions, majestic members of the Felidae family, are iconic symbols of strength, courage, and royalty, known for their golden fur and impressive manes. Found primarily in the savannas, grasslands, and scrub forests of sub-Saharan Africa, lions are apex predators renowned for their hunting prowess and social structure. They exhibit sexual dimorphism, with males distinguished by their large, flowing manes, which serve as a symbol of dominance and protect their necks during conflicts. Lions live in social groups known as prides, typically consisting of related females and their offspring, along with a few resident males. These prides form close-knit bonds through grooming, communal hunting, and mutual protection, with each member playing a vital role in the survival of the group. Lions communicate through a variety of vocalizations, including roars, grunts, and purrs, which serve to establish territory, coordinate hunts, and reinforce social bonds within the pride. As apex predators, lions primarily prey on a variety of ungulates, including zebras, wildebeests, and antelopes, employing coordinated ambush tactics to bring down their quarry. Despite their formidable hunting skills, lions face numerous threats, including habitat loss, human-wildlife conflict, and poaching for their body parts. Conservation efforts focused on habitat preservation, community engagement, and anti-poaching initiatives are essential for ensuring the survival of these magnificent creatures in the wild. Lions hold a special place in human culture and mythology, symbolizing power, courage, and nobility across diverse cultures and civilizations. Through education, advocacy, and responsible tourism, we can foster greater appreciation and conservation of lions, preserving their natural legacy for future generations to admire and cherish.</item>
        <item>Orcas, also known as killer whales, are highly intelligent and social marine mammals belonging to the Delphinidae family. These apex predators are characterized by their distinctive black and white coloration, robust bodies, and tall dorsal fins. Orcas inhabit oceans and seas worldwide, from the Arctic to the Antarctic, and they are found in both coastal and open ocean environments. Orcas live in tight-knit family groups known as pods, which are led by matriarchs and consist of multiple generations of individuals. They communicate through a complex system of clicks, whistles, and vocalizations, allowing for sophisticated social interactions and coordination during hunts. Orcas are formidable hunters, preying on a wide variety of marine species, including fish, seals, sea lions, and even other cetaceans. They employ coordinated hunting strategies, such as corralling prey and launching coordinated attacks, making them one of the ocean\'s most effective predators. Despite their name, orcas are not a threat to humans in the wild and rarely display aggressive behavior towards people. However, they face numerous threats, including habitat degradation, pollution, climate change, and disturbance from human activities such as boat traffic and noise pollution. Conservation efforts aimed at protecting orca habitats, reducing pollution, and mitigating human impacts are essential for ensuring the survival of these magnificent marine mammals. Orcas hold a special place in human culture and folklore, inspiring awe and reverence as symbols of strength, intelligence, and the beauty of the natural world. Through education, advocacy, and responsible stewardship, we can work together to safeguard the future of orcas and the oceans they call home.</item>
        <item>The parrot, belonging to the Psittacidae family within the Psittaciformes order, is renowned for its ability to mimic various sounds and human speech, alongside its intelligence and social nature. With strong beaks and feet enabling climbing and perching, these birds predominantly exhibit shades of green in their feathers, though color variations depend on the species. Found mainly in tropical habitats like rainforests and savannas, particularly in Southeast Asia and parts of Indonesia, parrots are highly social creatures, often seen in large flocks foraging in the wild or becoming cheerful members of the family as pets. Notable for their remarkable intelligence, they can be trained for tricks and to communicate with humans, but ensuring their well-being and happiness in domestic settings requires proper care and consistent attention.</item>
        <item>Snakes, elongated reptiles belonging to the suborder Serpentes, inhabit diverse ecosystems worldwide, ranging from tropical rainforests to deserts and grasslands. Characterized by their limbless bodies and flexible movements, snakes have evolved various adaptations for survival and predation. They come in a multitude of sizes, colors, and patterns, with some species equipped with venomous fangs for hunting while others rely on constriction to subdue their prey. Despite their often-misunderstood reputation, snakes play crucial roles in maintaining ecosystem balance by controlling rodent populations and serving as both predator and prey. Their keen sense of smell and specialized tongues aid in locating food and detecting potential threats. While some species are solitary, others exhibit social behaviors such as communal basking or mating aggregations. Snakes undergo remarkable physiological adaptations, such as shedding their skin periodically to accommodate growth and repair injuries. Though feared by many, snakes are fascinating creatures worthy of conservation efforts and respect within their natural habitats. Understanding their ecological importance and promoting coexistence is vital for preserving biodiversity and ecological harmony.</item>
        <item>The tiger, belonging to the genus Panthera and the family Felidae, is a large carnivore known for its grace, strength, and beauty. They are apex predators inhabiting various habitats, from rainforests to savannas, scattered throughout Asia, from Siberia to Indonesia. Tigers have fur ranging from brown to orange with distinctive black stripes, aiding in their camouflage in their environment. Tigers are renowned for their speed and agility in hunting, often ambushing their prey with remarkable precision. They are solitary animals, except during breeding, and maintain large territories that they carefully patrol. Tigers play a crucial role in maintaining ecosystem balance by controlling the populations of prey animals such as deer, wild boar, and monkeys. Despite being symbols of strength and elegance, tigers face serious threats, including habitat loss, illegal poaching, and human conflict. Strong conservation efforts are needed to protect tigers and the environments they inhabit so that this valuable natural heritage can be preserved for future generations.</item>
    </string-array>
    <integer-array name="data_photo">
        <item>@drawable/crocodile</item>
        <item>@drawable/deer</item>
        <item>@drawable/dolphin</item>
        <item>@drawable/elephant</item>
        <item>@drawable/gorilla</item>
        <item>@drawable/horse</item>
        <item>@drawable/lion</item>
        <item>@drawable/orca</item>
        <item>@drawable/parrot</item>
        <item>@drawable/snake</item>
        <item>@drawable/tiger</item>
    </integer-array>
</resources>